DAMON YOUNGER

Los Angeles, CA • 512-591-8511 • DamonYounger@pm.me • DamonYounger.github.io

PROFILE

15+ years of executive and practitioner experience in cybersecurity, software development, technology management, and R&D.

IT Management: I oversee IT programs and projects, manage teams and performance appraisals, develop and track budgets, and establish policies to achieve compliance and efficiency.

Cybersecurity: I expeditiously allow authorized access to company data. I ruthlessly deny unauthorized access. I rapidly respond to cybersecurity threats. And I prove all of the above.

Software: massive scale SaaS B2B products for manufacturing, services, retail, banking, finance, insurance, and health care.

Accomplishments: I've engineered and secured the most critical and complicated supply chains in the world for the largest companies in the Western economies.

EXPERIENCE

<u>Director of Cybersecurity Engineering & Architecture, Blue Yonder – 2022-Present</u>

- Serve on the CEO's Global Technology Review Board, the Product Architecture Review Board, and the corporate board Briefing Committee.
- Develop security programs and security projects that address identified risks and business security requirements critical to the CEO's go-to-market strategy, including: Risk Management, DR/
 Business Continuity, Risk assessment, Secure-by-design program, Threat models and Remediation, Global Attack Surface.
- Manage the process of gathering, analyzing, and assessing the current and future threat landscape, as well as providing the CEO with a realistic overview of risks and threats in the enterprise environment.
- Develop budget projections based on short- and long-term goals and objectives to meet the CFO's target cost.
- Monitor and report on compliance with security policies, as well as the enforcement of policies
 throughout the company to provide sales proof of security for the CMO, for regulatory compliance
 through the CFO, and to achieve the COO's operational objectives.
- Propose changes to existing policies and procedures to ensure operating efficiency and regulatory compliance, and to meet customer expectations for our SaaS offerings.
- Manage a staff of information security professionals, hire and train staff, conduct performance reviews, and provide leadership and coaching including technical and personal development programs for team members.
- Responsible for the following programs and teams:
 - Designed a secure, automated SSDLC process.
 - Corporate Software Standardization Initiative.
 - Zero-trust & Micro-segmentation Security Initiative.
 - Secure the CI/CD pipeline and post-production environments for thirty-two SaaS products.
 - Corporate and Customer IAM Team.
 - Defense in Depth Initiative: Endpoint, Network, Applications, Data.
 - Observability & Automation Team.
 - Critical Threat, Vulnerability, and Incident Response Team.

VP, Information Security, RUR (Startup) - 2020-2022

- Secured product range of next-gen multi-tenant, SaaS recruiting products.
- Cybersecurity architecture. Planning, buying, and deploying security infrastructure. Posture Management, Data Security, Vulnerability Assessment, Service Management.
- Data protection. Encryption, secure data in transit, data inventory, ACLs, retention policy.
- Cybersecurity governance. Establishing the frameworks and basis for SOC 2 and ISO certification.
- Application security. SSDLS, CI/CD, and secure by design libraries.
- Cyber-risk. Vulnerability assessments of APIs, data ingestion pipelines, and databases.

Sr. Manager of Automation, Genpact – 2017-2018

- Planned, staffed, and managed budgets for large, international security-intensive automation projects in Banking, Finance, Investor Relations, Insurance, Medicine, Manufacturing, and Government
- Conducted turn-around management of multi-million dollar projects in Banking, Finance, Insurance, and Medicine.
- Responsible for global cybersecurity standards and compliance for automation projects, including Secure-by-design program, Risk Management, Vulnerability Assessments, Risk Assessments, and Service Level Agreements.

Product Manager, S5 Stratos (Startup) – 2016-2017

- Managed product development teams for a retail logistics startup. Developed AI algorithms and technical approaches to scale web-based product for large retail companies.
- Created cybersecurity architecture including, Attack Surface analysis, Threat Models, Vulnerability Assessments, and Disaster Recovery scenarios.
- Transformed the user experience of the product into a visual composer rather than a statistical spreadsheet.

Sr. Manager, Disys - 2015-2016

- · Bootstrapped the company's robotic process automation team. Held budget responsibility.
- Created service teams: staffed and trained developer teams, trained marketing team, created presales and sales-support processes.
- Managed a portfolio of profitable RPA projects for companies in Technology, Medicine, Banking, and Insurance.

Manager of Enterprise Architecture, MetLife – 2010-2012

- Enterprise architecture: managed programs to deliver on the COO's go-to-market strategy.
- Cybersecurity reference architecture: Data Security, Application Security, Perimeter defense, Defense- in-depth, Vulnerability Assessments, Threat Response.
- Created company-wide data stewardship program and certifications for PIC and FINRA compliance. Built the technical plan for divestment of the bank's \$22 million mortgage portfolio, a daunting highly regulated endeavor.

EDUCATION

University of Dallas. Dallas, TX. – Philosophy & Mathematics 2004

SKILLS

Planning Budgeting & Forecasting • Early-stage Startups • Program Development • Project Management • Big Data • Supply Chain Optimization • Product Marketing • Anti-Money Laundering • Program Management Information • Technology • Risk Management • Cloud Computing • Information Security Management • ITIL • Disaster Recovery • IT Management • IT Strategy • Business Continuity • Vulnerability Assessment • Risk Assessment • IT Service Management • Vendor Management • Security Architecture • Solution Architecture • Cloud Architecture • Application Security • Budget Management • Al • Artificial Intelligence • LLM • Microservices • Turnaround Experience • Azure • Google Cloud Platform • AWS